Guide to the Peter E. Palmquist Collection of Male Photographers in the American West
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographic Materials, circa 1840-2003; Series II; (231 boxes)
  - Photograph Albums
    - Unidentified Photographers and Compilers
      - Photograph album of San Francisco and California, circa 1900 (Box 570)
      - Photograph album of California, including views of Lindsay, circa 1918-circa 1940 (Box 571)
      - Photograph album of a trip to Southern California, 1920 (Box 572)
  - Panoramic Photographs
    This subseries consists of panoramic photographs created by or documenting individual photographers and firms.
    Panoramic photographs depict wide broad horizontal images. They are produced by panoramic cameras or by joining photographs together.
    - Alva Art Studio, Group Portrait of Solders in the 91st Division of the United States Army, American Expeditionary Forces, possibly at Camp Lewis, Washington, circa 1919 (Box 573)
    - Bailey, Charles Z.
      - View of San Diego Bay and the first battleships through the Panama Canal, including USS Ohio (BB-12), USS Missouri (BB-11), and USS Wisconsin (BB-9); also includes the grounds for the Panama-California Exposition, 1915 July 28 (Box 574)
      - View of Theodore Roosevelt addressing Annapolis midshipmen in the Plaza de Panama at the Panama-California Exposition in San Diego, California, 1915 July 28 (Box 575)
      - Group Portrait of attendees at the American Legion, Department of California, Second Annual Convention in San Diego, California, 1920 August (Box 576)
    - Bunnell, Schuyler Ulysses
      - View of a lumber yard and harbor in Mendocino, California, circa 1910-1915 (Box 577)
      - View of the mill of the Mendocino Lumber Company in Mendocino, California, circa 1910-1915 (Box 578)
    - Cardinell-Vincent Company. Group portrait of the International Press Congress at Panama-Pacific International Exposition, San Francisco, California, 1915 July 6 (Box 579)
    - Givens, James David. Group portrait of men at the California Academy of Sciences, San Francisco, California, circa 1915 (Box 580)
    - Gordon, John C. Group portrait of attendees at the 20-30 International Eighth Annual Convention in front of the Scottish Rite Masonic Temple in San Jose, California, 1930 August (Box 581)
    - Keystone Photo Service Company. Group of sailors from the Pacific-Atlantic Fleet at Universal City Studios on the set for The Hunchback of Notre Dame in Universal City, California (Negative No. K6410), 1923 (Box 582)
    - Palmquist, Peter. Copy photograph of San Francisco, California, from Russian Hill, by Carleton Watkins in 1864, circa 1985 (Box 583)
    - Prince, George. Sailors from USS Ohio (BB-12), USS Missouri (BB-11), and USS Wisconsin (BB-9) at the Universal Film Manufacturing Company in Universal City, California, 1915 August (Box 584)
    - Scott, William A. Group portrait of the Grand Commandery of Knights Templars for California in San Francisco, California, 1922 April 22 (Box 585)
    - Thompson and Bingham. Group portrait of women in a courtyard in California (Negative Number 855), circa 1920 (Box 586)
    - Weaver Studio
      See: Box 558 (Oversize)
  - Framed Photographs
    This subseries consists of photographs in frames used by photographers or photography studios to market their photographs.
    - Eddy, Lindley. General Sherman Tree in Sequoia National Park, California, circa 1915 (Box 587)
    - Morse, George Daniels. Portrait of a young woman, circa 1870-1880 (Box 588)
    - Parmelee
      - Handcolored photograph of Yosemite Falls, Yosemite National Park, California, circa 1910 (Box 589)
      - Handcolored photograph of Gates of Yosemite, Yosemite National Park, California, circa 1910 (Box 590)
    - Weaver Studio. Panoramic group portrait of attendees at the 76th Imperial Council Session of the Ancient Order of the Nobles of the Mystic Shrine at the Los Angeles Memorial Coliseum, 1950 June 19-23 (Box 591)
    - Weidner, Charles. Handcolored photograph of Bridalveil Fall, Yosemite National Park, California, circa 1910 (Box 592)
    - Unidentified photographer, Portrait of a woman wearing a wedding dress, circa 1925 (Box 593)
      Housed in a frame purchased from P. J. Bachmann, 1908 S. Figueroa St., Los Angeles, California
- Additions from Other Collections, Series III
  - Research Files
    - Hickman, Paul Addison. 1979. "The Life and Photographic Works of George Fiske, 1835-1918" (Box 594)
      General
    - Thornbury, D. L. (Delmar L.), Songs of the Pacific. San Francisco: Thornbury Publishing Company, 1920 (Box 594)
  - Photographic Materials
    - Photographic Materials
      - Alaska, 4 (Box 595)
      - Arkansas, 10 (Box 595)
      - California, 16 (Box 596)
        - California, unidentified photographers, 46 (Box 596)
        - Howland and Taber family portraits, 6; Cartes-de-visite and cabinet photographs collected by Palmquist, as well as a family tree, that document the extended family of California photographers Benjamin Franklin Howland and Isaiah West Taber (Box 597)
        - Photographs of Mendocino County form the collection of Eugene Compton, 7 (Box 598)
        - San Francisco Earthquake of 1906, 9 (Box 599)
        - Picture postcards of sites in California, 22 (Box 600)
      - Colorado, 3 (Box 595)
      - Hawaii, 1 (Box 595)
      - Iowa, 174 (Box 601)
      - Kansas, 58 (Box 602)
      - Louisiana, 7 (Box 602)
      - Minnesota
        - Anderson, H. A., to Peavey, L., 70 (Box 603)
        - Peck, G. G., to Zimmerman, Charles A., and unidentified photographers, 26 (Box 604)
      - Missouri
        - Adams, R. F., to Lozo, Alex, 76 (Box 605)
        - Macurdy, J. C., to Wood, A. W., 77 (Box 606)
      - Nebraska, 27 (Box 607)
      - Nevada, 1 (Box 608)
      - North Dakota, 2 (Box 608)
      - Oklahoma, 2 (Box 608)
      - Oregon, 9 (Box 608)
      - South Dakota, 8 (Box 608)
      - Texas, 20 (Box 608)
      - Utah, 1 (Box 608)
      - Washington, 8 (Box 608)
    - Oversize Photographic Materials
      - Hartsook, Fred (Box 609 (Oversize))
      - Kytka, Theodore (Box 610 (Broadside oversize))
      - Unidentified photographer, "Now on exhibition, stereopticon views of the San Francisco ruins" (Box 611 (Broadside))
      - Unidentified photographer, Panoramic photograph of members of the Canton San Francisco No. 5, Independent Order of Odd Fellows (Box 612 (Broadside oversize))
      - Unidentified photographers in California, 4 (Box 609 (Oversize))
    - Photograph Albums
      - Slocum, Orville, circa 1865-1867 (Box 613)
        Photograph album related to the Slocum, a photographer active in Clear Lake, Ohio, and Austin, Minnesota, which chiefly includes carte-de-visite and tintype portraits of his extended family and friends
      - Waite, C. B. (Charles Betts) (Box 614)
        Photograph album that with photographs by Waite that chiefly document sites in Southern California, including Hotel del Coronado, Rancho Camulos, and homes in Los Angeles, as well as missions and churches, including La Iglesia de Nuestra Señora la Reina de los Ángeles, Mission San Gabriel Arcangel, Mission San Juan Capistrano, San Diego Mission, San Fernando, Rey de España, San Luis Rey Mission, and Santa Barbara Mission
    - Framed Photograph and Realia
      - Holmes, Alex, Studio portrait of five men posed standing and sitting with guitars and mandolins, framed photograph, circa 1900 (Box 615 (Oversize))
      - Masonic apron of Thomas Washington Wells from Tuolumne Lodge No. 8, Grand Lodge of Free and Accepted Masons of the State of California, Free and Accepted Masons, 1882 (Box 616 (Oversize))
    - Photographic Negatives
      - Lummis, Charles Fletcher, Glass plate negatives of sites in the American Southwest, 1888-1913; 28 (Box 617)
      - Schuffler, Chas
        - Glass plate negatives of sites in Vacaville, California, circa 1914; 48 (Box 618)
        - Glass plate negatives of sites in Vacaville, California, 48 (Box 619)
        - Glass plate negatives of sites in Vacaville, California, 38 (Box 620)
      - Unidentified photographer
        - Glass plate negatives of sites in Plumas County, California, 55 (Box 621)
        - Glass plate negatives of sites in Plumas County, California, 12 (Box 622)
        - Contact prints from glass plate negatives of sites in Plumas County, California, 69 (Box 623)
      - Unidentified photographer
        - Film negatives of Crater Lake, Oregon, and sites in northern California, 92 (Box 624)
        - Contact prints from film negatives of Crater Lake, Oregon, and sites in northern California (Box 625)
      - Unidentified photographers, Glass plate negatives, 8; Glass plate negatives created by discrete unidentified photographers that include a studio portrait, as well as interior and exterior views. Identified images include a stereographic view of the Summit House at Mount Washington, New Hampshire, circa 1875, and a view of the intersection of First Street and Fountain Alley in San Jose, California, circa 1878-1883 (Box 626)
      - Unidentified photographers, Film negatives, 38; Film negatives by discrete unidentified photographs of interiors and exteriors, as well as copy negatives created by Palmquist, including portraits of baseball teams related to the Fireman's Fund Insurance Company (Box 626)
    - Lantern Slides
      - Kemp, Edward H., 74 (Box 627)
      - Kemp, Edward H., 35 (Box 628)
      - Tibbitts, H. C., 30 (Box 628)
      - Tibbitts, H. C., 72 (Box 629)